charmants.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Charmants.com

We have created this Privacy Policy to explain Charmants.com's information-gathering and dissemination practices. Your use of our service confirms your acknowledgement and acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## I. What information do we collect?

i. Personally Identifiable Information  
We only obtain and retain personally identifiable information that you give to us and certain related transactional information which we collect based on your use of our service. For example, you might supply your email address by contacting us. You also may supply personally identifiable information, including your name, email address, and location in the course of making comments on Charmants.com. Charmants.com enables users to submit links to third-party content residing on other websites. In order to use the submission feature, users must use a third-party login service or create an account with Charmants.com. When creating an account, users are required to submit certain personally identifiable information to us (a username and the user's email address), and a password, which is not necessarily personally identifiable.

ii. Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
When you visit our service, we do not collect data about who you are or any other personally identifiable information except as described above. We do, however, collect certain non-personally identifiable information about you based upon your activity on our website. We may collect machine data such as processor type, processor speed, operating system type, browser type, audio devices, modem devices, and video cards. This information may include the Web site's Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address.

iii. Cookies  
Cookies are small data files that are sent from our servers to your computer during a browsing session. In order to make Charmants.com more responsive to the needs of our visitors, we may use cookies to assign your Internet browser a unique random number, a sort of anonymous user ID that is stored in a file on your computer. By using a cookie, we are able to automatically identify your browser and track your use of our service and our web pages. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but contain an option for you to turn off the acceptance of cookies if you prefer. You can also delete cookie files from your computer after they have been stored. We use third-party companies to serve ads, manage our feed-based communications and provide alternative login solutions. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. For example, Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads to our service, and those ads place cookies on your computer. However, those cookies do not reveal any of your personally identifiable information. Google provides information about their advertising and privacy, including how to opt out of the use of their DART cookie at the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

## II. How do we use the information we collect?

i. Personally Identifiable Information  
We use the email address you give us when you create your Charmants.com account for moderation and password recovery purposes only. We do not use any personally identifiable information you may include in your comments; but your posts will be viewable by other users. We do not monitor comments and we are not responsible for any third-party use of the information you include in those postings. We do not sell, rent, loan, or otherwise share personally identifiable information, including email lists, with third parties. We may be required by law, court order, governmental agency, or law enforcement authority to disclose whatever personally identifiable information we may have collected from you. We may also disclose your information to law enforcement authorities investigating suspected illegal activity. We do not combine personally identifiable information with any of the non-personally identifiable information gathered through the use of cookies.

ii. Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
We compile and analyze non-personally identifiable information on an aggregated basis. For example, we may know that fifty people visited this Privacy Policy yesterday or how long the average visitor spent using our service last month. But we do not link this information with any of the personally identifiable information that we collect from you, for instance the information you give us when you create your Charmants.com account. We may also use this non-personally identifiable information to conduct internal research on our visitors' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand and serve our visitors. We also pass the aggregated data (but not your personally identifiable information) to advertising agencies and firms that conduct site analysis, such as Google Analytics, in order to help such companies feed advertising to our service in the most efficient manner. We do not restrict the recipients of any non-personally identifiable information from using that information. We do not monitor third-party use of the information we share with them. However, none of that information can be used by third parties to identify you.

## III. How long do we retain the information we collect from you?

We retain your Charmants.com account information and the aggregated non-personally identifiable information we collect from you indefinitely. We also retain the comments submitted by users indefinitely. We do not currently have any purging policy. 

## IV. Can you request that we purge from our system the information we collect from you?

We do not currently have any procedure by which users can request that we purge the information we collect from them. However, the only personally identifiable information we collect is the Charmants.com account information and the information you may contribute about yourself when you post comments. You may change (or delete) your Charmants.com account information at any time, although in doing so it does not necessarily mean that the original account information will be deleted from our servers. We have no policy about deleting comments you made from our system. 

## V. What measures do we take to protect the security of the information you submit?

Our website, and all of the data related to the service, reside on servers maintained by a commercial hosting company. That company takes certain precautions to protect the servers from intrusion, including securing the facilities in which the servers are located and maintaining a firewall to protect against unauthorized access. None of these measures is foolproof; and we do not monitor the web hosting company's facilities or procedures to determine its compliance with the security procedures it says it employs. 

## VI. How will you know of changes to this Privacy Policy?

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy to comply with applicable laws, to improve your experience, or to reflect any general change in our policy. Any changes we make to this Privacy Policy will be posted to this web page. We will not send you messages informing you of these changes, so you are responsible for checking this web page frequently. You are encouraged to print or download a copy of this document for your permanent records. The date of the most recent revisions will appear at the bottom this page. 

## VII. How can you contact us if you have any questions?

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or our practices or procedures with regard to personally identifiable information, please use our Contact page. 

Effective date of this Privacy Policy: October 29, 2009
